Jade Kirkham



jadekirkham@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/jade-kirkham



(801) 808-3951



https://jadekirkhamportfolio.herokuapp.com/

Summary

I spent the first 7 years of my professional career working in Customer Relations / Tech Support. I spent the next 2 years working as a Commerical Electrical Apprentice. Since then, I have found a passion for coding, unlike any other that I have experienced, and I am dedicated to making this my future. I have just graduated DevMountain and am looking for the right company to grow my roots with!

Technologies:

- React
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- SQL
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
- HTML5
- Chrome Developer Tools
- GitHub
- Visual Studio
- Git

Experience



Student

Devmountain

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021 (6 months)

I have now fully completed the DevMoutain program and have published my works through my current website: https://jadekirkhamportfolio.herokuapp.com/



Electrical Apprentice

Natural Power

Apr 2019 - Apr 2021 (2 years 1 month)

I decided I had enough Customer Relations experience and decided to make a shift into a different field. I spent 2 years working as a Residential and Commercial Electrical Apprentice for a smaller company where I was expected to learn the trade quickly and to be responsible for my portion of work. I also went through 2 semesters of Electrical College at MTECH before switching back to an IT field



Case Manager

Wayfair

Nov 2017 - Jan 2020 (2 years 3 months)

As a Case Manager, I would receive an amount of "escalated" issues daily that I was responsible to resolve and follow-up on in a timely fashion.

Frontier Capital One Credit Specialist

Frontier Communications

Jan 2016 - Nov 2017 (1 year 11 months)

I worked for Frontier Communications on a project for Capital One where I would handle inbound calls regarding customers accounts, credit cards, and interest rates. I was also selected to be apart of several smaller projects to try and make Customer Service within Capital One updated company-wide

Tier 1 Tech

PcCareSupport

Apr 2015 - Jan 2016 (10 months)

Worked as a Computer Technician, remotely connecting to customers computers to run scans, diagnose issues and resolve any found malware.

X Regional Customer Manager

Xyngular Corporation

Jun 2012 - Jan 2014 (1 year 8 months)

After High School, I worked as a Customer Service Representative for a Nutritional Company. Here I worked up to a specialized role where successful customers in the NW region would contact me directly for assistance.

Box Office Attendant

Cinemark

Dec 2010 - Jun 2012 (1 year 7 months)

Began working as an Usher cleaning theaters after showings. I was then moved to the Concessions area and eventually earned my position in the Box Office.

Education



Web Development

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021

Lehi High School

High School Diploma, General Studies 2009 - 2012

Skills

React.js • JavaScript • Node.js • Electrical Troubleshooting • Customer Relationship Management (CRM) • Agile Methodologies • Scrum • MySQL • Chrome Developer Tools • GitHub

Honors & Awards



2nd Place Utah Entrepreneur - SkillsUSA

2011

Created a business model with my group to modernize the commerical industry on live television by implementing some sort of live download reward system that would allow viewers to download coupons they could use if they watched the entire commercial.



Eagle Scout - Boy Scouts of America

2012

I loved scouts so much in my early teens, I completed enough merit badges to almost earn 2 Eagle Scout awards! For my final project, I selected a team to manage building a display cabinet for our local city museum.